Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother James.
>> Yes, sir. And God spake all these words,
saying, I am the Lord thy God, which
have brought thee out of the land of
Egypt, out of the house of bondage. Thou
shalt have no other gods before me. Thou
shalt not make unto thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I,
the Lord thy God, am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me, and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Sixth day shalt thou labor
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work. Thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hollowed it. Honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shalt not kill.
Thou shalt not commit adultery. Thou
shalt not steal. Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shalt not covet thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not covet thy neighbor's
wife, nor as man's servant, nor as
maid's servant, nor as ox, nor is ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. I
read Exodus 20:es 1-17. May the Lord add
a blessing to the reading of this word.
In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> So, here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague questions
as well as the long scripture questions
and the questions of debate. We are not
here to debate. We are here to spread
the true gospel of Jesus. So, please be
as direct as possible with your
questions so we can be as direct as
possible with our answers out of the
King James Bible. No other Bibles or
books will be acknowledged on this
program. Also, keep in mind this is a
live stream, so feel free to send in
your questions that pertain to
everlasting life. We just asking that
you keep them to a two scripture
maximum. But let me introduce to you the
family that's on the panel this evening.
We got brother Julius. Good evening
everybody. Brother Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Jamone, rest in peace.
>> Brother James,
>> good evening everyone.
>> Sister Deborah,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Sean,
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question? Uh there are
several heldover questions that will be
answered first before getting into
tonight's Q&A.
Victor Holly asks in Ezekiel 19 1 and
two. Who is the lioness?
>> All right. Ezekiel 19. Let's go there,
brother James.
>> When you get there, brother, pick it up.
Read one and two. And the guest caller
will take it from there on. Who is this
lioness?
>> Okay. Ezekiel 19 1 and 2 says,
"Moreover, take thou up a lamentation
for the princes of Israel and say, what
is thy mother, a lioness? She laid down
among lions. She nourished her welps
among young lions."
Okay, it really tells you what it's who
it's talking about in the beginning in
the very first verse when it say take up
a lamentation for the princes of Israel.
These are the rulers of Israel and the
lioness that's that's represent the
nation of Israel. And we're going to
show you that uh uh how that Israel uh
uh uh
was ended how after Solomon death Israel
split. Then you had the northern kingdom
which maintain the name of Samaria
or just Israel or Ephraim. Then you have
the southern kingdom that's Judah. So
now these uh let you know what she's
telling you here is that uh uh uh that
this woman represent
a lioness in the 12th chapter of
revelation. It also describe her as a
woman
with the uh uh the moon under her feet
with and and she's clothed in the sun
and she had a crown of 12 stars upon her
head. three 12 crowns upon her head
which represent the 12 tribes of Israel.
Now this is telling you that the
northern tribe was taken out
first
because while Israel was intact they
were pretty rough. Let me show you what
happened to them to the northern tribe.
Let's go into second kings
because we in fact before we go there
let's read a little more. Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Let's go let's read let's let's read
from uh read verses three and four.
>> Okay.
>> Verse
verse three says
>> and she brought up and she brought up
one of her welps. It became a young lion
and it learned to catch the prey. It
devoured men.
>> Uhhuh.
>> The nations also heard of him. He was
taken in their pit and they brought him
with chains unto the land of Egypt.
>> Now we know that that never happened.
But Egypt to us is captivity. So now
what happened was uh the nations come
together and then especially one with
help took down the northern kingdom. Now
let's go into second Kings 7th chapter
17th chapter rather we're going to read
first read five and six then we're going
to skip
2 Kings 17 five and six first
>> okay 2 Kings uh verse 17:5 says then the
king of Assyria came up throughout all
the land and went up to Samaria and
besieged it three years.
In the ninth year of in the ninth year
of Hosa, the king of Assyria took
Samaria and carried Israel away into
Assyria and placed them in Halah and in
Habbor by the river of Goran and in the
cities of the Mes.
>> Now, I mean, Esther took Israel all of
the northern tribes. Skip down to verse
22 and read 22 and 23.
Okay, it says, "For the children of
Israel walked in all the sins of
Jeroboam, which he did, they departed
not from them until the Lord removed
Israel out of his sight, as he had said
by all his servants, the prophets." So
was Israel carried away out of their own
land to Assyria until this day.
Okay. Now, that was the first young lion
that the lionist uh uh uh uh had raised
up.
It was tough while it was still the
nation, but the Assyrians took them away
and they have not returned to the land
even to this day. But now, but she
raised up another young lion. Let's
let's start start reading. Let's go back
to Ezekiel the 19th chapter. We're going
to start at verse five.
19 and five. We're going to read from 5
to 9.
>> Okay. Ready when you get there.
>> Okay. It says,
>> "Now when she saw that she had waited
and her hope was lost, then she took
another of her welps and made him a
young lion. And he went up and down
among the lions. He became a young lion
and learned to catch the prey and
devoured men.
And he knew their desolate places, and
he laid waste their cities, and the land
was desolate, and the fullness thereof
by the noise of his roaring.
Then the nations set against him on
every side from the provinces, and
spread their net over him. He was taken
in their pit, and they put him in war in
chains, and brought him to the king of
Babylon. They broke him into holds that
his voice should no more be heard upon
the mountains of Israel.
>> Okay. So now that was Judah. So Judah
was raised hell too. They was rough
while they wash uh intact. But then
Nebuchadnezzar, king of Babylon. And the
Babylonians came and they knocked off
the nation of Judah.
So now when they knocked off the last
one they knocked off was Zedekiah and
Israel have not been a nation since.
That's why he said they never heard his
voice no more upon the mountain of
Israel. Let's go and show you when that
who did that. Nebuchadnezzar. Let's go
into 2 Chronicles
36th chapter.
We're going to read 11 11 through13
first.
>> Okay. 2 Chronicles 36:11-13
says, "Zedekiah was 1 and 20 years old
when he began to reign and reigned 11
years in Jerusalem. And he did that
which was evil in the sight of the Lord
his God, and humbled not himself before
Jeremiah the prophet, speaking from the
mouth of the Lord." And he also re
rebelled against King Nebuchadnezzar who
had made him swear by God. But he stiff
ne stiffened his neck and hardened his
heart from turning unto the Lord God of
Israel.
>> So now
Zedekiah was set up by Babylon and God
had had broken a deal between
Nebuchadnezzar because he wanted to try
and have some uh uh part of the nation
still intact. But Jedekiah rebelled
against God and Nebuchadnezzar. So look,
so skip down and read from 17 to 20.
Let's see what happened.
>> Okay, it says, "Therefore, he brought
upon them the king of the called deeds,
who slew their young men with the sword
in the house of their sanctuary, and had
no compassion upon young men or maiden,
old man, or him that stooped for age. He
gave them all into his hand. And all the
vessels of the house of God, great and
small, and the treasures of the house of
the Lord, and the treasures of the king,
and of his princes. All these he brought
to Babylon.
And they burnt the house of God, and
break down the wall of Jerusalem, and
burnt all the palaces thereof with fire,
and destroyed all the godly vessels
thereof.
And them that had escaped from the sword
carried he away to Babylon, where they
were servants to him and his sons until
reign of the kingdom of Persia.
So now Nebuchadnezzar took down the
nation of Judah, southern kingdom.
And uh
we have not had a king from that day to
this one. So the first young lion
Israel, all of all the the the uh the
lionist represent Israel
and the first young lion represent the
northern kingdom which is Samaria and
the next young line that she sent forth
represent Judah. And both of them have
been taken in taken out by the nation
and have not been heard anymore upon the
land of Israel or either the mountain of
Israel. That's all it represents. So the
line is is Israel. That's all I have to
say.
>> All right. Thank you for that. We hope
that answered your question as we move
on to our next question.
>> Moving on. Melon natural journey asks,
"Is it is a woman supposed to sleep in a
separate bed during her monthly?"
>> So when a woman is on her monthly,
should she sleep in a separate bed?
Brother Dre, what you say?
Let's go to Leviticus 15. Leviticus 15
and we going to pick it up at verse 19.
Leviticus 15 and 19. Go ahead, Brother
James.
>> And if a woman have an issue, and her
issue in her flesh be blood, she shall
be put apart seven days. And whosoever
toucheth her shall be unclean until the
evening.
>> Go ahead. And everything that she lieth
upon in her separation shall be unclean.
Everything also that she siteth upon
shall be unclean.
>> Go ahead.
>> And whosoever toucheth her bed shall
wash his clothes and bathe himself in
water and be unclean until the evening.
>> One more verse. And whosoever toucheth
anything that she set upon shall wash
his clothes and bathe himself in water
and be unclean until the evening. So
whatever she touch the bed, wherever she
go, she cooking your dinner, whatever
the case may be, you cannot get around
this unless you totally separate
yourself.
But at the end of the day,
what about somebody else that touch a
door knob and you touch that knob?
How you getting around that? Verse 22.
Go ahead. And whoso whosoever toucheth
anything that she set upon shall wash
his clothes and bathe himself in water
and be unclean until the evening.
>> Yes, sir. So now
skip down to verse uh 32 and 33.
>> Okay. 32 says, "This is the law of him
that hath an issue, and of him whose
seed goeth from him, and is defiled
therewith."
>> Go ahead. and of her and of her that is
sick of her flowers and of him that hath
an issue of the man and of the woman and
of him that lith with her that is
unclean
>> right now that that is not talking about
you lying with her in terms of being
intimate let's go and look at that real
quick Leviticus 18 and 19
Leviticus 18 verse 19 and that's that.
>> Okay. It says, "Also, thou shalt not
approach unto a woman to uncover her
nakedness as long as she is put apart
for her uncleanness."
>> Right. Exactly. So, at the end of the
day, sir, I can't tell you how you
should deal with that, but the scripture
says what it says.
That's all I got.
All right, thank you for that, brother.
As we move on to our next question,
>> moving on. Valencia wants you to explain
Galatians 4 10 and 11.
>> Galatians 4:10 and 11. Can you shed some
light on that, Brother Dre?
>> Yes, sir. Let's go to that Galatians 4
and we going to pick it up at verse 8.
Galatians 4 and verse 8.
Go ahead.
>> How be it then, when ye knew not God, ye
did service unto them which by nature
are no gods.
>> So when you didn't know God, you did
service unto them which by nature are no
gods. Go ahead. But now, after that ye
have known God, or rather are known of
God, how turn ye again to the weak and
beggarly elements, where unto ye desire
again to be in bondage.
>> Ye observe days and months and times and
years.
>> Now, go ahead. Go ahead, brother.
>> I am afraid of you. least I have
bestowed upon you labor in vain.
>> Now people read this to say this is
talking about the Sabbath and all of
that. And if that is the case, let's
look at something Paul did. Let's go to
Acts the 17th chapter. Acts 17 and read
verses 1 and two. Acts 17 1 and two.
This is not talking about the Sabbath.
This is telling you about what they did
before they came into the word. Acts
17:1 and2. Go ahead, brother. Now when
they had passed through Amphibious and
Appalonia, they came to Thessalonica
where was a synagogue of the Jews. And
Paul, as his manner was, went in unto
them, and three Sabbath days, reasoned
with them out of the scriptures. So Paul
reasoned with them out of the scriptures
three Sabbath days.
Skip. Let's go over to Acts 18 now and
read verse one. Acts 18 and verse one.
Go ahead, brother.
>> After these things, Paul departed from
Athens and came to Corinth.
>> Verse four. Go ahead.
And he reasoned in the synagogue every
Sabbath and persuaded the Jews and the
Greeks.
>> He reasoned in the synagogue every
Sabbath. So if this was talking about
Sabbath days and observing days, then
Paul would be a hypocrite, wouldn't he?
>> But Paul is not a hypocrite. Paul kept
the commandments of God. Skip down to
verse 11 and read that, brother.
And he continued there a year and six
months teaching the word of God among
them.
>> That's right. Skip down to 19. Go ahead.
>> And he came to Ephesus and left him
there. But he himself entered into the
synagogue and reasoned with the Jews.
>> Uh-huh. When they desired him to tarry
longer time with them, he consented not,
but bade them farewell, saying, "I must
by all means keep this feast that cometh
in Jerusalem, but I will return again
unto you if God will."
>> And he sailed. Mhm.
>> It's keeping feast days here. I got one
more place. Let's go to Acts 20. Acts 20
and look at something there.
Acts 20 verse 15 and 16. Go ahead.
>> And we sailed thence and came the next
day over against Shields. And the next
day we arrived at Samos and terried at
Trigillium. And the next day we came to
Mitus.
>> For Paul had determined to sell by
Ephesus because he would not spend the
time in Asia. for he hastened if it were
possible for him to be at Jerusalem the
day of Pentecost.
>> Paul kept the day of Pentecost. So Paul
was keeping these days. And if we read
Acts 13, it'll tell you that the whole
city came together the next Sabbath
after Paul preached on the Sabbath day.
So no, this is not talking about the
Sabbath. If somebody try to tell you
that now you know that it's not cuz we
just read about three or four scriptures
saying so also Jesus
his custom was to keep the Sabbath day
and you can read that in Luke 4 and 16.
That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for that brother.
as we move on to our next question.
>> Moving on, we have two questions on
fringes that I'm going to combine. Marx
uh asks, "Is it a sin to wear fringes?"
And Smoothie asks if what is the
importance of wearing franches?
>> All right. So,
brother Julius, what about these
fringes?
>> Oh, you're on mute, Julius.
>> Thank you. Is it a sin to wear fringes?
The answer is no.
What is the importance of wearing
fringes? Uh, sin is the transgression of
the law. 1 John 3 and4. Sin is the
transgression of the law. It is not a
sin to wear fringes. But the other
question is what is the importance of
wearing fringes? I would ask the
question this way with the understanding
that the Lord has blessed us with. What
was the importance of wearing fringes?
Let's go to numbers the 15th chapter and
find out why they were given to you.
Everybody wants to make it our culture.
It was never our culture.
Never our culture. Let's get to the
bottom of this right here. Numbers 15,
James, and pick this up in verse 32.
>> Okay. Numbers uh 15 and 32 says,
>> "Yes, sir."
>> "And while the children of Israel were
in the wilderness, they found a man that
gathered sticks upon the Sabbath day."
>> Not supposed to be doing no work on the
Sabbath day. Go ahead and read.
>> And they that found him gathered sticks
brought him unto Moses and Aaron, and
unto all the congregation.
and they put him inward because it was
not declared what should be done to him.
>> So they put him in wart. That mean they
locked him up because they didn't know
what to do with them. So they had to
inquire the Lord. Go ahead.
>> And the Lord said unto Moses, "The man
shall be surely put to death. All the
congregation shall stone him with stones
without the camp.
>> The wages of sin is death." Go ahead and
read. And all the congregation brought
him without the camp, and stoned him
with stones, and he died. Go ahead.
>> As the Lord commanded Moses.
>> Yes. And the Lord spake unto Moses,
saying, "Speak unto the children of
Israel, and bid them that they make them
fringes in the borders of their garments
throughout their generations, and that
they put upon the fringe of the borders
a ribband of blue." Now, so the Lord
because a man has sinned and to keep
from killing the the people and the
nations, the Lord said, "Make you some
fringes and put it on your garment." Go
ahead and read
>> 39. It says, "And it shall be unto you
for a fringe,
>> for a culture,
>> for a fringe."
>> Uh-huh.
that ye may look upon it and remember
all the commandments of the Lord and do
them.
>> Oh, that you may look when you see the
fringe, it will remind you don't sin.
Don't sin. That's what the fringes were.
That was the importance of the fringe to
remind you to keep to remember all the
commandments of the Lord. And what else?
James. And that ye seek not after your
own heart and your own eyes, after which
you use to go ahory,
>> that you lean not to your own
understanding.
One more. Verse 20. Verse 40.
>> That ye may remember
and do all my commandments and be holy
unto your God. Because to keep the Lord
from killing the people, he say, "Put
you a French,
a a garment of blue." And that you may
remember it was never your culture.
Never your culture. So therefore, that's
what the importance of fringes was. Now
the Lord that was added, it was not
added to the ten commandments. That was
a added law to remember. So because of
sin, another added law, animal sacrifice
because of sin. So he took away the
animal. When Jesus came and shed his
blood, that ended fringes
because the blood of bulls and goats
could not take away sin. The fringes was
given to you as a reminder so that you
won't sin. Wages of sin is death. He
took that away. The next thing that the
Lord is going to take away is the grave
or death. So two out of the three things
that was added is gone. So death was
added to the creation because man sin.
Fringes was added because man sin.
Animal sacrifice was added because sin.
So two of those things are gone. So when
the Lord come back, he's going to uh
abolish the death uh sisters and
brothers.
And that would be the end of that
because the shed blood of Jesus covered
those things. Not the animals, not the
fringes. It was never your culture. How
do I know? Because in the book of Acts
when Paul was going walking around the
uh the Roman soldier asked him, you
know, he should have asked him, "Are you
if that was your culture?" He would have
asked him, "Uh, I see your fringes." But
Paul didn't wear fringes. John the
Baptist never wore fringes. It was for
that generation. So John the Baptist had
on camel's hair.
No fringes.
Anybody want to add to that? That was
the importance of to remember to remind
you to keep the law so the Lord wouldn't
kill you. That's all I got. Cornell.
>> All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered that question as we move on to
our next one.
>> Yes. Moving on. Edward Barber asks, "How
many nations are the Gentiles?"
The Gentiles consist of how many
nations, brother Jerome.
>> The easiest answer I can give you is
that Genesis 10. I'm I'm not going to
try to count them, you know. We just
going to read and I'll let you count
them. Okay? But let's go to um Genesis
the 10th chapter uh read verse one. Read
verse one. Then we'll read the rest of
them afterwards.
>> Okay. Now these are the generations of
the sons of Noah, Shim, Ham, and
Japheth. And unto them were sons born
after the flood.
>> Okay. Now, Shim, I just want you to know
cuz this people out here saying that,
you know, Israelites
are are Gentiles.
Israelites trace through Sheim. Okay.
But Noah had also he had Ham and Jfhat
and it's out of JFAT the gent the prog
he's the progenitor of the Gentiles who
are commonly called Europeans. Okay. All
right. So go ahead keep reading.
>> The sons of Japheth Gar and Mega and Ma
and Jan and Tubal and Mach and Tyrus.
And the sons of Gar, Ashkenaz, and
Rifad, and Togamar, and the sons of Jan,
Elishot, and Tarsus, Kdum, and Dodon.
By these were thes of the Gentiles,
divided in their lands, everyone after
his tongue, after their families, and
their nations.
>> Okay, so these are the Gentiles. All
right. So, um sometimes that genealogy
can can be kind of confusing because the
man carried the seed and when when that
man happened to lay with a woman that's
of another nation, for example, I know
so many uh
Israelites
I that have married European women
and I've seen the offspring
of the two
and a lot of times their offspring look
like Europeans
but that offspring
if the father is the Israelite I don't
care how he look that offspring is
Israelite
okay and and I know you've seen that
okay so you can't always go by how what
the color is to determine what their
nationality is. But when you look at
this Genesis 10, okay, these are the
people that are referred to as Gentiles
from verse 1-5.
That's all I got on it.
>> All right, thank you for that. As we
move on to our next question,
>> moving on. MJ asks, "What's the origin
of the called Deans?"
the origin of the called deans, brother
Jerome.
>> Uh well, that kind of that kind of
depends on uh what people you referring
to. Uh and what I mean by that is let's
go to this Genesis 11 uh 31 cuz
Abraham's people and uh among other
Seemetic people they was dwelling in
occupying this land that was called the
land of the calans.
Okay before the Gentiles was there. All
right. So let's go look at that. Genesis
11:31.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
>> And Terara took Abram his son, and Lot
the son of Haran, his son's son, and
Sarai, his daughter-in-law, his son,
Abram<unk>s wife, and they went forth
with them from the Calaldes to go into
the land of Canaan, and they came unto
Haron and dwelt there.
>> Mhm. So now Abraham, his wife, and you
know these other people mentioned in
this verse, they weren't Gentiles. They
came out of um Sheim. They trace back to
Shim. Okay, they don't trace to to JF,
but it talk about them being in the land
of or the calans.
Okay. But later on, you know, the
Europeans who are are called possessed
that that that land. Okay. And they
start referring to them as called. And
most of the time when you read in the
Bible when it when when the Bible be
talking about called
most of the time they talking about the
Gentiles like Nebuchadnezzar, so on and
so forth. These are Europeans. All
right. To occupy the land of the called
deans. All right.
They possessed it later. All right. So,
uh
I want to show you some examples uh uh
of that. You know, let's go to Jeremiah
32 verse 28.
I'm I'm gonna take you to three places.
You know, uh, most of the time when you
see called Dan, they talking about the
European.
>> That's what we talking about. So, go to
Jeremiah 32, read verse 28.
>> Okay. It says, "Therefore, thus sayeth
the Lord, behold, I will give this city
into the hand of the called deans and
into the hand of Nebuchadnezzar, king of
Babylon, and he shall take it."
>> Okay. King Nebuchadnezzar is is a called
in. You know, he king of the king of
Babylon. Okay, let's tie that with the
fourth chapter. Stay in Jeremiah, go to
the fourth chapter and read verse 3-4.
>> All right. U fourth chapter verses 3 and
4.
Correct. Jeremiah 4.
>> Yeah. And we gonna skip five.
>> Okay. It says, "For thus sayeth the Lord
to the men of Judah and Jerusalem, break
up your fow ground and sew not among
thorns.
Circumcise yourselves to the Lord and
take away the foreskin of your heart, ye
men of Ye men of I'm sorry about that.
Ye men of Judah and inhabitants of
Jerusalem. Least my fury come forth like
fire and burn that none can quench it
because of the evil of your doings.
>> Well, they didn't do what they were
supposed to do. They didn't hearken to
the Lord. And what did the Lord do? Read
verse 6 and 7.
>> Set up the standard toward Zion. Retire.
Stay not for I will bring evil from the
north and a great destruction.
>> He said he going to bring evil from the
north. Keep reading.
>> The lion is come up from his thicket,
and the destroyer of the Gentiles is on
his way. He has gone forth from his
place to make thy land desolate, and thy
city shall be laid waste without an
inhabitant.
>> Okay, so these people that the Lord
going to use to bring evil to uh against
Judah, they out of the north, and he's
referring to them as Gentiles. Okay. So
now one more place go to the 25th
chapter
of Jeremiah and pick it up in at verse
89 and that'll be it.
>> Okay. It says Jeremiah 25:8-9
says, "Therefore, thus saith the Lord of
hosts, because ye have not heard my
words, behold, I will send and take all
the families of the north, saith the
Lord, and Nebuchadnezzar the king of
Babylon, my servant, and will bring them
against this land, and against the
inhabitants thereof, and against all
these nations round about, and will
utterly destroy them and make them an
astonishment and a hissing and a
perpetual desolations.
>> Yeah. So I I just wanted to show you
that most of the time when you see
called in talking about the Gentiles,
okay, Europeans,
that's all I got on.
Oh, I think brother Cornell you're we
can't hear you.
>> Okay. Should I move on? The time is
8:09.
>> Yeah.
log off and come back in corn.
>> All right, I will go on to the next
question and he can come in and we'll
deal with that one.
The next question is uh Jeffrey Dre and
Dre will have this question. Jeffrey
Meyers asks for you to explain how
tender mercies translate into eternal
life in Acts 13:34
and Isaiah 55:E3
is given again explain how tender
mercies translate into eternal life and
that is Dre. Okay. So, let's go to that
Acts 13 and we're going to uh pick it up
at verse 32 and read to 34. Brother
James, Acts 13
and we're going to pick it up at verse
32 and read to 34. Go ahead when you get
it.
>> Okay.
And we declare unto you glad tidings,
how that the promise which was made unto
the fathers, God hath fulfilled the same
unto us their children, and that he hath
raised up Jesus again, as it is also
written in the second psalm, thou art my
son, this day have I begotten thee.
>> So this Jesus is the one that he raised
up, and these are the glad tidings. And
that just as he raised up Jesus, he is
the firstborn among many brothers to
come. These are glad tidings. Go ahead,
brother.
>> And as concerning that he raised him up
from the dead, now no more to return to
corruption.
>> He said on this wise, I will give you
the sure mercies of David.
>> That's right. The sure mercies of David.
Now, let's go over to Isaiah 55 and we
going to read verse one there. Isaiah 55
and 1.
Go ahead when you get it, brother.
>> Okay.
>> Isaiah 55 and1 says, "Holdo, everyone
that thirsteth, come ye to the waters,
and he that hath no money, come ye buy
and eat. Yay, come buy wine and milk
without money and without price.
>> That's right. Verse three. Go ahead.
>> Incline your ear and come unto me. Hear
and your soul shall live and I will make
an everlasting covenant with you, even
the sure mercies of David.
>> And that we talking about Jesus right
here. He is the sure mercies. But let's
go over to Psalm 132 and look at
something there. And I got one other
place after that. Psalm 132
and we're going to pick it up at verse
11. Psalm 132 and verse 11. Go ahead.
>> The Lord has sworn in truth unto David.
He will not turn from it. Of the fruit
of thy body will I set upon thy throne.
>> That's right. Go ahead.
>> If thy children will keep eat my
covenant and my testimony that I shall
teach them, their children shall also
sit upon thy throne forever more.
>> He said, "Of the fruit of thy body will
I set upon thy throne." Now skip down to
verse 16. Go ahead.
I will also clothe her priests with
salvation, and her saints shall shout
aloud for joy. That's right. Now, let's
go to Acts 2, and we going to read
30-32. Acts 2:30-32.
>> Go ahead. Acts 2:30-32
says,
"Therefore, being a prophet and knowing
that God has sworn with an oath to him
that of the fruits of his loins
according to the flesh, he would raise
up Christ to sit on his throne."
>> So, this is who it was talking about.
Jesus Christ. He is the sure of mercies.
Go ahead.
>> He's seen this before. Spake of the
resurrection of Christ. that his soul
was not left in hell, neither his flesh
did see corruption.
>> This Jesus hath God raised up whereof we
are all witnesses. Are all we are we all
are his wisdom. We all are witnesses.
>> That is good. Look, I gotta go here.
This is it. Acts 4. Acts four,
we're gonna read verses 10 and 12. And
that is it. Go ahead, brother.
>> Be it known unto you and to all the
people of Israel that by the name of
Jesus Christ of Nazareth, whom he
crucified, whom God raised from the
dead, even by him doeth this man stand
here before you whole.
>> Read verse 12, brother. Go ahead.
Neither is there salvation in any other.
For there is none other name under
heaven given among men whereby we must
be saved.
>> And this is how this eternal life is
given to us. But we get that life and we
must walk in these commandments. We
confess and like it says in Exodus 20
and6 he says he shows mercy onto them
that love him and keep his commandments.
That's all I got on that.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered that question. My
apologies for my technical difficulties
as we move on to our next question. Yes,
the time is 8:15 and uh brother Cornell,
I'm going back to be alert question
where be alert asks, must you anoint
your head prior to each fast? Daniel 10
verse3
he says, "Did Daniel do a true fast?" A
lot of people call it the Daniel 21 day
fast.
>> All right. Well, I haven't read anywhere
where you have to anoint your head
before you do a fast, that is a choice
of yours. You want to get anointed
before your fast. Okay. And if you just
want to begin your fast without
anointing, okay, let's let's go to
Daniel 10. Daniel 10. And let's see.
Because when you do a fast according to
the scripture, it is nothing by mouth.
No food, no water, no anything when you
do a fast. But let's go and read Daniel
10 and let's pick it up at verse two
because Daniel was looking for an answer
too and he eventually got it. But Daniel
10 and verse two, go ahead.
In those days I Daniel was mourning
three full weeks.
>> So he was mourning three full weeks. And
what else? I ate no pleasant bread.
Neither came flesh nor wine in my mouth.
Neither did I anoint myself at all till
three whole weeks were fulfilled.
So Daniel was saying here that he didn't
eat any pleasant bread and neither came
flesh nor wine into his mouth and
neither did he anoint himself until
three whole weeks were finished because
he was looking for an answer but it
didn't say here that he did a fast. It
was just saying that he didn't eat
certain things here and he said that he
did not anoint himself while he was
waiting on this answer. So, um, it
doesn't say that Daniel did a fast, but
like I said, a fast according to the
scriptures, nothing by mouth, no food,
no water, no anything. So, as far as
anointing with oil, that's your choice.
If you decide you want to anoint before
your fast or not, that is up to you.
That's all I got.
All right, we're going to leave it right
there as we move on to our next
question. Moving on. Be alert. Uh, be
alert says the urum and the
can you please explain how they were
used by the priest to give revealed
answers? What happened to those stones
and will they be used in Jesus kingdom?
>> All right. quite a bit in that question,
but I'm going to ask the guest caller to
take it from there about the urum and
the thumb and as well as Jesus kingdom
and these stones.
Well, the truth of the matter is there's
not enough. I can really give you a
definition of these of of the uh uh yum.
And it didn't necessarily mean that
there's stones. They were put in the in
the uh uh
you know the vest when Aaron went in
>> among the stones.
>> Truth of matter is
don't have about two places that speaks
about them. All I know is that they are
with the priest, the Levites, and uh uh
uh
it says no more about it.
That's all I have to say. I can't answer
the question because uh I don't know
really if these are really stones or was
just something among the stones. All I
know is that they was with the priest
and where they are now.
I suppose they stopped went with the
with the Levitical priesthood when Jesus
came and started the new covenant. But
the truth of the matter is I don't know
what they are and where they are. Don't
have to say.
>> All right, we'll leave it right there as
we move on to our next question.
>> Moving on. Cool. Blue says, "I'm only 27
and I know you can't teach until 30. Am
I wrong for finding scriptures and
teaching others what we are supposed to
be doing and why I try to spread the law
to them and why we do it? Do I stop?"
>> All right, Julius. What do they do with
all that information they got?
No, you're not wrong for teaching. You
just can't stand in front of uh a
congregation and be behind the pull pit.
>> Let's go to Numbers the 4th chapter.
Numbers the fourth chapter.
Numbers four, James. And when you get
it, read verse one and then we going to
step down to verse three.
>> Okay?
>> It says
>> there is a protocol, sisters and
brothers. Go ahead and read.
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses and unto
Aaron, saying
>> from uh verse three.
>> From 30 years old and upward, even until
50 years old, all that entered into the
host to do the work in the tabernacle of
the congregation.
>> Now you outside the congregation, but
the thing about it is from 30 years old
because you said you know you have to be
30. So you understood you understand
this. So uh from 30 years skip down to
verse 23.
>> From 30 years old and upward until 50
years old shalt thou number them. All
that enter in to perform the service to
do the work in the tabernacle of the
congregation.
>> Now one more verse. Verse 30. So we can
get there three times a time. Go ahead.
from 30 years old and upward, even unto
50 years old, shalt thou number them.
Everyone that enterth into the service
to do the work of the tabernacle of the
congregation. Now, let's go to Luke.
Notice from 30 years old. Why 30 years
old? Because that was the law and that
was the protocol based upon judges right
here. I'm sorry, based upon numbers.
Now, let's go to Luke the 2 chapter
because a lot of people trying to say
Jesus did this when uh uh he he started
his ministry. No, he didn't start his
ministry. The book don't say he started
his ministry at that. He can't give the
law and then turn around and break the
law. Luke chapter 2. Luke chapter 2,
James, and pick it up at verse 40. I
believe I want Luke 2
>> and 40. When you get it, go ahead,
brother. And the child grew and waxed
strong in spirit, filled with wisdom,
and the grace of God was upon him.
>> Talking about Jesus, how old was he at
42? Verse 42.
>> And when he was 12 years old, they went
up to Jerusalem after the custom of the
feast.
>> Now, what was Jesus doing at in that
temple? F verse 46.
And it came to pass that after three
days they found him in the temple
sitting in the midst of the doctors both
hearing them and asking them questions
>> not teaching and he was full of the Holy
Spirit but he was 12 years old. Now if
you go to the let's go to the third
chapter of Luke he had to wait Luke the
third chapter and pick it up at verse
23.
because the protocol cannot be broken.
Go ahead.
>> And Jesus himself began to be about 30
years of age being as was supposed the
son of Joseph which was the son of Hel.
>> You can read the rest of them on your
own. You have to be 30 years old to to
stand before the people and teach the
word of God in the behind the pull pit
in the congregation. Now, it's good
because that is our that that's what we
assigned to do. Preach the gospel to
every creature. It is good that you are
27 years old and that the zeal of the
Lord is upon you to teach the word of
God. Yes, you can answer some questions
if you know some questions. Yes, you
could go and spread the gospel. But to
officially do it, you have to be 30
years old according to the scriptures.
Moses 40 years old. And then uh when the
Lord called him, Moses was he grew up in
Egypt, but the Lord called him at 40
years old. So uh but the and that's the
protocol because the protocol cannot be
broken. And it's a good thing. No, you
don't stop answering questions and
teaching people and and uh uh uh sharing
the word of God with people. But to
stand behind the pull pit before the
congregation got to be 30 years old. I
hope that helped. Cornell.
>> Mhm. All right. So, Cool Blue, keep
letting that light shine for anybody
that wants to hear the true word of God.
All right. We're going to keep moving
along, Sister D.
>> Yes. Moving on. Johnny O says, "If I
can, I don't have a question, but a
prayer request. I'm spinning off into
alcoholism
and I'm having a hard time stopping my
drinking. Can you brothers pray for me
as I pray for myself?
>> All right, guest caller. We have a
problem here with alcoholism.
>> What is it that we can do according to
this question to be of help?
All you can do is encourage him to stand
up and find the strength to do it
himself. Because no matter how hard is
praying, this is something that's not
beyond his control.
I say what you do is you pray for
yourself and let this be the beginning
of you controlling
yourself. cuz uh until you decide that
you're not going to drink anymore, all
the prayers on the planet is not going
to help you. Not even yours.
Cuz this is not something that's uh uh
beyond your control
like a illness or something like cancer
or some kind of sickness. This is a
state of mind that you have to reach
like when you decide to turn to the Lord
and get baptized.
You have to come to that conclusion.
Otherwise, you're not going to do it.
But the only answer I have for you is
to the Lord give you strength and just
stand up and be a man of God and stop.
All I have to say. Mhm. Yep. And
sometime
if I may be allowed in addition to
though what GC just said understand the
health risk that come along with it.
>> You know what what what it does to your
body in the long run.
>> Yep. And and sometimes too AA meetings
can help because you have other people
in there who have had the same problem
but have overcome their addiction. So
there's things that can be offered to
you. So, please seek them out. All
right, we're going to continue as we
move on to our next question.
>> Next question. The bayou perspective as
in Exodus 13 verse1 17 when God
redirected the Israelites to encamp by
the Red Sea sea was it to avoid a war
that was already taking place in the
land of the Philistines.
>> All right, we're going all the way back
to Exodus. Jerome, what about this Red
Sea here?
>> Before I read, we read that verse,
um, it's kind of self-explanatory,
you know. Uh, the Lord knew that Israel
had just came, he just brought them out
of the land of Egypt. It was 400 year
captivity in Egypt. And the Lord knew he
they a no stomach for no battles against
no Philistines. They didn't have no
stomach for no battle against the
Egyptians when they came at them at the
Red Sea. The Lord knew that. So, you
know, just read the verse and whatever
what what that verse says, that's that's
the answer. It's self-explanatory. So,
let's read the verse and that's the
answer. Okay. So, uh, Exodus 13:17,
>> "And it came to pass when Pharaoh had
let the people go that God led them not
through the way of the land of the
Philistines, although that was near, for
God said, least pre-adventure the people
repent when they see war." And they
returned to Egypt.
>> Yeah. So, you know, that's implying a
hey, if the if them Philistines
seek them out and to go to war with him,
Israel, Lord know, Israel, they ain't
had no stomach for it. So, that's why he
took him another way. All right. If
anybody want to add something, they
came.
>> All right. We're going to leave it right
there as we move on.
>> Moving on. Sister L. Israel asks, "In
the first book of Chronicles, did God
only record the children who walked in
his ways?"
>> All right. So, the first book of
Chronicles, I mean, is that the whole
first Chronicles or are they talking
about Chronicles
one and one? But the question is
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. What's the question, Deborah?
>> Right. Uh and no verse is given. They
just says, "Did God only record the
children who walk in his ways?"
No, I see it mentioned in a lot of
nations here. We go to that 1 Chronicles
1 and one. But let's open it up to the
panel because based on their question,
they're leaving it open for all the
books of first Chronicles or the first
Chronicles first chapter.
So, um let's go let's just read that.
Let's go to the uh 1 Chronicles and
let's pick it up and see that it
mentions more than just Israel here.
Okay,
>> pick it up in there. Verse four.
>> Verse four. Noah, Shim, Ham, and
>> So, that mentions earlier what uh
Brother Jerome, you you covered some of
that, didn't you?
>> Yeah. when um
>> well if you talking about the whole book
of Chronicles uh the guest caller dealt
with um
>> Nebuchadnezzar and um you know uh
and there's a few other nations you know
that war and came against Israel and and
you know they wasn't serving God.
Nebuchadnezzar wasn't a servant of God
in the sense that the Lord used him to
destroy Judah in that sense he was a
servant you know that's all I
>> yeah right so the question they want to
know did God only record the children
who walked in his ways
>> the answer the answer is no
>> right the book of kings and the book of
chronicles mirror itself It dealt with
Israel. It dealt with the nation that
came in in contact with Israel. The book
of Chronicles verseh
and 2 Chronicles and so forth uh are
mirrors first and 2 Kings. So therefore
it just it's it's a historical record uh
of people walking in God's ways and
people not walking in God's ways.
>> Yeah. And I mean in the book in the
first chapter of Chronicles, it it talks
about the lineage of Edom and and all of
his dukes as well. So no,
it doesn't
to answer that question.
>> Yeah. So that's about all we can give
you
um in pertaining to how that was left
open, but we hope that that was of help
to you, Sister Deborah. We going to move
on.
>> Yes. Moving on. Smoody says, "If we are
under the new covenant, why are you all
still teaching and preaching to people?
Didn't Jesus say that he would put his
laws in our minds and hearts?"
>> All right, guest caller.
>> You know, we are under the new covenant.
And
anybody that thinks that the Lord going
to go into your chest and do your head
and do surgery, they don't understand
the new covenant, just like the old
covenant, it started with the blood.
back when uh uh uh back when when when
Israel when God made a covenant with
Israel,
he started and then he sprinkled the
people with the blood and then he told
them according to the uh uh the uh
according to the uh uh uh covenant that
God made with you, you know, you he
sprinkling them with the blood. So the
same thing with the new covenant with
the new old covenant with the new
covenant. Let's go into Hebrews the 10th
chapter and we going to read a couple
things 10 and one first.
>> Okay. Hebrews 10:1 says, "For the law
having a shadow of good things to come,
and not the very image of the things,
can never with those sacrifices which
they offered year by year continually
make the comers there unto perfect."
>> Now skip down on verse six and find and
continue and we see why they couldn't
make them perfect.
>> Verse six, you said,
>> "Yeah." Okay. In burnt offerings and
sacrifices for sin, thou hast had no
pleasure.
>> I'm sorry. No, I'm I'm sorry. Verse
four.
>> Verse four. Okay. For it is not possible
that the blood of bulls and of goats
should take away sins.
Wherefore, when he cometh into the
world, he saith, Sacrifice and offering
thou wouldest not, but a body hast thou
prepared me.
Go ahead.
>> In burnt offerings and sacrifices for
sin, thou hast had no pleasure.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Then said I, lo, I come in the volume of
the book, it is written of me to do thy
will, oh God.
>> Go ahead. above when he said, "Sacrifice
and offering, and burnt offerings, and
offering for sin, thou wouldest not,
neither had pleasure therein, which are
offered by the law." Go ahead.
>> Then said he, "Lo, I come to do thy
will, oh God, he taketh away the first,
that he may establish the second."
>> Now, he took away the first what? the
first covenant that he may establish the
second they couldn't coexist. So how did
he do that? Keep reading. By the which
will we are sanctified through the
offering of the body of Christ once and
once for all.
Now, that is when the old covenant was
done away with and the new covenant came
in for four. Skip down to verse 14 and
read to verse 17 and this kicks the rest
of it in. 14- 17. Go ahead and read.
>> For by one offering he hath perfected
forever them that are sanctified,
whereof the Holy Ghost also is a witness
to us. For after that he had said
before, "This is the covenant that I
will make with them after those days,
sayaeth the Lord, I will put my laws
into their hearts, and in their minds
will I write them, and their sins and
iniquities will I remember no more."
>> Now, when did he do that?
>> When did that start? It started with the
new covenant. What verse are you reading
now? That was 17, sir.
>> Okay. So, now the covenant was
instituted the day that Jesus died
because the blood is what starts a
covenant. The blood just like the old
covenant was started the same way. Let's
go into uh uh uh
Exodus the 20.
Let's see. Exodus chapter 34.
We're going to read one and skip down to
verse 4 and five
and we're going to skip down to verse 27
and 28.
>> Okay. So, uh, Exodus 34:es 1, then we're
going to skip to 4 and 5.
>> Okay? So, I'll start at one. And the
Lord said unto Moses, "Hue thee two
tables of stone like unto the first, and
I will write upon them these tables, the
words that were in the first tables
which thou breakest."
>> No, I'm uh uh uh Okay, go ahead. Get
down to four and five. Four and five
now.
>> And he hewed two tables of stone like
unto the first. And Moses rose up early
in the morning, and went up to unto
Mount Si, as the Lord had commanded him,
and took in his hand the two tables of
stone. And the Lord descended in in the
cloud, and stood with him there, and
proclaimed the name of the Lord.
>> Okay. Now, these two, what verse was
that?
>> That was verse five. Sir,
>> skip down and read verse 27 and 28.
>> And the Lord said unto Moses, "Write
thou these words, for after the tenor of
these words, I have made a covenant with
thee and with Israel." And he was there
with the Lord 40 days and 40 nights. He
did neither eat bread nor drink water.
And he wrote upon the tables the words
of the covenant, the ten commandments.
Now, we're going to show you how that he
consummated that covenant. Now, back up
to Exodus 24 and read from 3 to 8.
>> Exodus 24:es 3-8 says,
"And Moses came and told the people all
the words of the Lord and all the
judgments. And all the people answered
with one voice and said, "All the words
with the which the Lord has said, will
we do?" And Moses wrote all the words of
the Lord and rose up early in the
morning and built an altar under the
hill at 12 pillars according to the 12
tribes of Israel. And he sent young men
of the children of Israel, which offered
burnt offerings, and sacrificed peace
offerings of oxen unto the Lord. And
Moses took half of the blood and put it
in basins, and half of the blood he
sprinkled on the altar. And he took the
book of the covenant and read in the
audience of the people. And they said,
"All that the Lord had said, will we do
and be obedient."
And Moses took the blood and sprinkled
it on the people and said, "Behold the
blood of the covenant which the Lord
hath made with you concerning all these
words."
>> Now what did he did when they entered
and when they that was the first the
first covenant he read and all the
people agreed that they was going to do
it. Then he took it and he sprinkled the
book and he sprinkling the people. And
then he's uh you know according to uh uh
uh uh you know
according to the words of these covenant
according to the uh uh uh the blood uh
to behold the blood of the covenant had
to have death had to have sprinkling of
the blood. So now Jesus wasn't going,
you know, he didn't come and sacrifice
the animals. He had to go to another
place. But let's see what had to happen
first for him to create uh start the new
covenant. Let's go to Hebrews the 9th
chapter and read verses and we're going
to start reading at verse 11
cuz we're going to read a little bit
because I'm putting a little time into
this because you got to want people got
to understand about the covenant when it
starts
9 11
and we're going to do a little read.
Read the 20. Go ahead.
>> Okay. But Christ being come and high
priest of good things to come, by a
greater and more perfect tabernacle, not
made with hands, that is to say, not of
this building.
Neither by the blood of goats and
calves, but by his blood, his own blood,
he entered in once into the holy place,
having obtained eternal redemption for
us.
For if the blood For if the blood of
bulls and of goats, and the ashes of an
hepher sprinkling the unclean
sanctifieth to the purifying of the
flesh, how much more shall the blood of
Christ, who through the eternal spirit
offered himself without spot to God,
purge your conscience from dead works to
serving the living God.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And for this cause, he is the mediator
of the New Testament.
That's because he shed That's because he
shed his blood, not the blood of an
animal. The word testament mean
covenant.
>> Yes, sir.
>> So, by the mediator of the new testament
or the mediator of the new covenant, go
ahead and read. that by that by means of
death for the redemption of the
transgressions that were under the first
testament they which are called might
receive the promise of eternal
inheritance.
>> Go ahead.
>> For where a testament is, there must
also of necessity be the death of the
testator.
>> Why? Why? Why? Where the covenant is,
there also must be the death of the one
that make the covenant. So that mean is
that he had to die because it's the
blood
that makes the covenant. Go ahead and
read
>> verse 17. For a testament is a force
after men are dead. Otherwise it is of
no strength at all while the testator
liveth.
Whereupon neither the
>> Mhm.
>> Oh yeah. whereupon neither the first
testament was dedicated without blood.
For when Moses has spoken, every precept
to all the people according to the law,
he took the blood of calves and of goats
with water and scarlet wool and hissup
and sprinkled both the book and all the
people, saying, "This is the blood of
the testament which God hath enjoined
unto you."
>> Now, we read that, didn't we?
Yes, sir. It's
>> testimony. This is the blood of the
covenant. It is the blood that starts
the covenant.
That's why I say let me may uh take away
the old that he might establish a new.
Did you finish that?
>> Yes, I finished verse 20. Did you want
me to read 21?
>> No. Now, I want you to go to uh uh
let's let's go to uh uh Zechariah the
9th chapter, read verse 9 and skip down
and read verse 11.
>> Says Zechariah the 9th chapter
and verse 9. Correct?
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. Rejoice greatly, O daughter of
Zion. Shout, "Oh daughter of Jerusalem,
behold, thy king cometh unto thee. He is
just and having salvation, lowly, and
riding upon an ass, and upon a coat, the
fo of an ass."
>> Verse 11.
>> As for thee also, by the blood of thy
covenant, I have sent forth thy
prisoners out of the pit, wherein is no
water.
See the covenant is started. The old
covenant was started when Moses
sprinkled the people with the blood of
animals.
And when Jesus died, he sprinkled the
people with his own blood. That's why I
say take away the old the old covenant
that he might establish the new
covenant. It is an error to think
that because everybody don't know the
law immediately that the new covenant
haven't kicked in. It is the blood that
established the covenant. Isn't this
what we just got through reading?
>> Yes, sir.
>> So now, what about the rest of it? Bar
going to put your laws in your in your
inward part. That is simple. You do that
every day. Let's go into Acts 8 chapter
and read 29 uh uh verses 29 and 28.
>> Chapter vers 29
and 28.
>> I mean 32 I'm sorry verse 29 to 32.
>> Okay. So that's verse
verse I'm sorry. Acts 8.
>> Uhhuh.
>> 29-32. Correct.
Okay. Then the spirit saith unto
Philillip, "Go near and join thyself to
this chariot." And Philip ran thither to
him, and heard him read the prophet
Isaiah's, and said, Understand thou what
thou readest?
And he said, How can I except some man
should guide me? And he desired
Philillip that he would come up and sit
with him. The place of the scripture
which which he read was this. He was led
as a sheep to the slaughter and like a
lamb dumb before his shear. So open he
not his mouth.
>> Now skip down to verse 35.
>> Then Philillip opened his mouth and
began at the same scripture and preached
unto him Jesus.
That's how the Lord is going to put his
laws into your mind by teaching you.
>> But the covenant
>> is already in force.
>> So to think that that everybody don't
know the law that you ain't under the
new covenant. That's because you ain't
paying no attention. It is the blood
that the covenant is established on. The
blood established the old covenant and
the blood of Jesus have established the
new covenant. You are under the new
covenant. That's why I said by the blood
of thy covenant have I set forth thy
prison out of the pit wherein there is
no water. It is the blood that starts
the covenant.
>> Yes sir.
>> Not
>> that everybody don't know it. Eventually
you will.
>> Yeah.
say but the blood is starting in the
covenant. The Old Testament started with
in the New Testament
and said point blank don't start as long
as there until there is until there's
the depth of the testator.
>> So Moses use animals and Jesus use own.
You are under the new covenant.
>> That's all say
>> y
had in there. Why are you all still
teaching and preaching to the people?
That's what Philip did when he went down
there. And when Jesus came out the
grave, he said, "Go ye into all the
world and preach the gospel to every
creature."
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's it.
>> Covenant has been established. New
covenant.
>> Yes, sir. All right. Thank you for that.
And we hope that that answered your
question, Sister Deborah. Time checkers.
We keep it running.
>> Yes. Let's move on. The time is 8:49.
Peggy asks, "Why was the name of the
area Palestine
given as an insult?"
>> All right, Julius, what you say?
>> The name Palestine is not biblical. It
was named after the Philistines.
Pharaoh Ramsey's III in the 12th century
conquered the southern coastal people of
uh the land of Canaan. That's what you
read in the Bible, the land of Canaan.
The Canaanites grew up there, the seven
nations of the Canaanites. And by the
time, and so, uh, that was the Egyptian
name of it, they call it Palisette.
By the time the Greeks came along, they
call the land Syria Palestine.
Then the Romans came along because they
could, whoever conquer you could rename
you. they could relocate your people,
take the original inhabitants and put
other people in your land. So by the
time Emperor Hadrien came along, he
changed the name to Palestine.
All it is is a region of territory, not
an insult. It's a region of territory.
So it's not written as an insult. It is
written whatever your conqueror call
you. So that's why the name is called
Palestine. But it was named after the
Philistines who originally the Egyptian
called them the Palisett. And then the
ancient Hebrews call them the Palisette.
But by the time the uh Greeks came along
they called it Syri Palestinian
Palestinian. And then the Romans came
along and changed it to Palestine.
It's just like the uh just like the Sea
of Galilee when Jesus came on the scene.
It was before he came on the scene. It
was called the uh uh Sea of Galilee. But
when Rome conquered it, they called it
uh the Tiberia Sea. So when somebody
conquer you, they can name you whatever
they want to name you.
That's the best I can do. That doesn't
mean it's an insult. It's just that
they're going to give you a name. From
Judah to Judea, the Romans called them
Judea. That's all it is. Just a name
change of a territory.
All right, thank you for that. Hope to
answer that question as we move on to
our next one.
>> Next one. Brother Anthony Horsey says,
"Can you please share some light on Acts
24 verse 24?" I had a brother ask me how
Dusilla, the wife of Phil Felix, was
called a Jewish when her father Hera
agria was an Edomite.
This must be an error or misprint. I
know that the man holds the seed and we
are what our fathers is. However, are
there any scriptures to correct?
>> All right. Why don't we go there to Acts
24 and 24
dealing with Dusilla?
And when you get there, brother, reading
the guest caller, take it from that.
>> Okay. Acts 24 and 24 says, "And after
certain days when Felix came with his
wife Drusilla, which was a Jewish, he
sent for Paul and heard him concerning
the faith of Jes of faith of faith in
Christ."
>> Now, I have a question. Just like he put
the axe where he said that she was
Jewish. I like how come he didn't put
the scripture in there to show that she
was Hera's daughter.
>> Great question.
>> He must have been reading one of them
lost books
>> cuz ain't nothing in the King James
regular that we use that said that she
was era's daughter.
So we ever asked the question where did
they get it out of? They didn't get it
out of this book
and those of us that deal with this King
James version and tell you in the
Revelation the 20th chapter and the
books was open. They would judge out of
the things that are written in this book
>> according to their works. So now I give
a person that asked the question I give
you a challenge. find out in the King
James version that where it said that
she was uh uh uh Herod a gripper's
daughter and educate us. That's all I
got to say.
>> Yeah. In this book cuz in all fairness
we tell you in the beginning of the
program that this is the only book that
we acknowledge on this program. All
right, let's move on to new territory.
Right, Deborah? Yes, we are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday, September
the 3, 2025.
Shangquila A Joby says, "Was Mary
actually pregnant with the word or was
Jesus truly God himself?"
Like is Jesus the astral god or just the
word of God
which in turn makes him God?
All right, let's open that up to the
panel.
>> Okay, I want I want to say this here.
Why don't people pay attention to what's
written in the book? Go to Hebrews the
10th chapter, read one one verse, but
we've been there before tonight, verse
one, and then skip down to uh uh uh uh
verse two of uh verse two and continue.
>> Okay. Hebrews 10:11
says, "For the law having a shadow of
good things to come, and not the very
image of the things can never with those
sacrifices which they offer year by year
continually make the comers there unto
perfect."
>> Skip down to verse uh uh uh
uh what's verse two. Because the blood
of bulls and goats is in verse four.
>> That's verse four, sir. Verse four, go
ahead and read.
>> For it is not possible that the blood of
bulls and of goats should take away
sins.
>> Where wherefore when he cometh into the
world, he saith, sacrifice and offering
thou wouldest not, but a body has thou
prepared me.
>> Yes.
>> So now uh uh uh go ahead, read the next
verse. In burnt offerings and sacrifices
for sin, thou has had no pleasure.
>> So now what happened was
father made a body just like he made the
first man
and Jesus took his body over and uh it
was planted into
this woman. It was Jesus.
Now let's go into uh uh Isaiah the 7th
chapter
and we going to show you about where it
said a virgin care conceive
and we going to pursue that a little bit
7th chapter. It said let's let's see
where uh
>> verse 14. Yeah. You want to start at
verse 14 sir?
>> Yeah go ahead.
Isaiah 7:14 says, "Therefore, the Lord
himself shall give you a sign. Behold,
>> pay attention. Pay attention to what it
said. The Lord himself shall give you a
sign." Go ahead.
>> Behold, a virgin shall conceive and bear
a son, and shall call his name Emmanuel.
>> Uhhuh.
But
>> a virgin shall conceive
and shall bear a son and shall call his
name Emmanuel. Now let's go and see what
that man what that mean what that name
means.
Take us into Matthew the first chapter.
Let's see.
>> Matthew 1 I think 23. You want?
>> Okay. 1 and 23.
>> Read it.
>> Behold, a virgin shall be with child and
shall bring forth a son, and they shall
call his name Emmanuel, which being
interpreted is God with us.
>> There you go.
>> God is with us. Okay. So God, so Jesus
is is called the word because he is the
spokesman.
You ain't never heard nobody's voice but
his
go St. John the 5th chapter and read
verse 37.
John 5 and 37 says,
"And the father himself which has sent
me hath borne witness of me. Ye have
neither heard his voice at any time nor
seen his shape."
Now, so he is a spokesman. The voice
you've been hearing all this time is
Jesus. He's the one that spoke to Moses
and all the prophets. He is. And this
same Jesus
took over a body that the father made
and he became a part of his creation.
That's uh one of the places where and I
leave it alone where he said he he uh uh
became like his brother. He took upon
him the seed of Abraham. I know it's in
Hebrews.
Let's see.
>> Search mode. We are in that.
I think in Hebrews the second chapter
and let's see.
>> Yeah. Uh verse 16.
>> Verse 16.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. What's it say?
>> For verily he took not on him the nature
of angels, but he took on him the seed
of Abraham.
>> Go ahead.
Wherefore in all things it behooved him
to be made like unto his brethren that
he might be a merciful and faithful high
priest in things pertaining to God to
make reconciliation for the sins of the
people.
Now, soon Jesus
was God. Just like the father was God is
God.
And this man messed up. And the only way
for this man to be delivered
is is is for a man to die for him. So
the Lord checked. He couldn't find a man
on this whole planet cleaning up to die
for him. So what he did? He took upon
him the seed of Abraham. But the Lord
made this body out and and brought and
and uh gave it to out of this uh uh
Jesus came through the seed of Abraham
born by a virgin Mary.
That's why and then it says his name
shall be called Emmanuel. That mean that
God is with us. So the word wasn't like
the word became flesh. The spokesman's
became flesh.
And how body was made for him? Just like
God formed a man out of dust of the
ground, he took over that body. The body
was planted into the woman by the hand
of an angel. And he was born into the
family of man.
That's all I have to say.
>> Yes, caller. Can we go to that 1 Timothy
3 and 1 verse 16?
>> Okay.
>> 1 Timothy 3:16. This for any naysayales
that just don't believe this.
>> First Timothy 3 and 16 James.
>> And without controversy,
>> without controversy,
>> great is the mystery of godliness.
God was manifest in the flesh, justified
in the spirit, seen of angels, preached
unto the Gentiles, believed on in the
world, received up into glory.
>> That's it in a nutshell.
>> All right. So, we hope that that
answered your question and shed some
light upon you. And sister Deborah,
let's do one more question and we will
close the evening.
>> Yes. Heather May uh asks, "Can you take
pay time off for fee stays? Even though
I'm not working, I will still be earning
income. Can you take paid time off for
fee stays?"
>> Yeah, you work for that.
you put in for your vacation day and you
work for that.
>> But she say even if she don't have a
job, but she working for herself, right?
If that's what she said. Uh she I don't
uh I don't know if she's just taking off
that's why she's not working but she's
still earning or what she meant by even
though I'm not working I still will be
earning income.
>> It said don't do no survival work. It
didn't say don't receive no income.
It said don't do any survive work. So if
you're not working then you're not
breaking the law. All
right.
All right. We hope that that answered
your question, Sister Deborah. Time
check
>> 9:04.
>> We have ran out of time and we want to
thank everybody from all around the
world who joined in with us this evening
and asking those great questions. And we
say until we all come together. Again,
keep in mind that if you submitted a
question and we have a chance to get to
it, don't resubmit it. Sister Deborah,
take it, put it in rotation, and we will
address that question next week. So,
until we all come together again, be
safe, be careful. May the Lord bless us
all and stay prayed up as brother James
close us out. Our Father, which art in
heaven, hallowed be thy name. Thy
kingdom come, thy will be done, in earth
as it is in heaven. Give us this day our
daily bread, and forgive us our debts as
we forget of our debtors, and lead us
not into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the
power, and the glory forever. in Jesus
name we pray. Amen.